Guide to the Ira Nowinski collection, ca. 1965-2000
Department of Special Collections
Ira Nowinski collection,
ca. 1965-2000
Mss Photo 440
Nowinski, Ira
10 linear ft. (ca. 15,000 photographs and negatives)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The collection consists of two major subdivisions. The first is negatives and prints from Nowinski's Holocaust collection totalling some 6,250 images and 1,548 prints, and includes the following projects: "In fitting memory; the art and politics of Holocaust memorials," the Segal Holocaust Memorial, the 50th anniversary Warsaw ghetto uprising, and the opening of the U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum. The second subdivision is Judaica photographs, totalling some 8,905 images. This segment includes three projects: the Karaite Jews, Israel, and the Soviet Jews of San Francisco.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions on access.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 2001.
Biography
Ira Nowinski is an American photographer of Polish and Hungarian Jewish descent. Born ca. 1942 and raised in New York, he was the first person in his family born in the United States. At the age of 42, he was prodded by opera singer Regina Resnick to do a photo essay around the Jewish milieu. He had previously done photo essays of the North Beach, San Francisco, area, of the evacuation of elderly citizens from hotels in the South of Market area of San Francisco, and of the Southeast Asian Community in the same city. In addition, he had been the staff photographer of the San Francisco Opera since 1978.
Working first with Resnick and then with Seymour Fromer of the Judah L. Magnes Museum, Rhonda Abrams of the Anti-Defamation League, Anita Friedman of Jewish Family & Children's Services, and the Northern California Board of Rabbis, Nowinski began documenting the Jewish experience in the San Francisco Bay Area. One of his first projects was to document Soviet Jews who had immigrated during the 1970's and 1980's.
He also photographed the Karaite Jewish Community in Foster City. The Karaites were a Jewish community that had lived for nearly 500 years in Egypt. The Arab-Israeli war resulted in the expulsion of the Jews from Egypt at the conclusion of that conflict. Many subsequently immigrated first to Israel and then to Northern California. Nowinski retraced their migration route in reverse, first photographing Karaites in Foster City, California, then in Israel, and finally in Egypt.
Nowinski and Sybil Milton of the U.S. Holocaust Museum did a joint work on the Holocaust Memorials throughout Europe, Israel, and in the United States. This work, entitled "In fitting memory: the art and politics of Holocaust memorials" combined text provided by Milton with Nowinski's photographic essay of the monuments documenting the millions of Jews who lost their lives under the Nazi regime.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
The collection consists of two major subdivisions. The first is negatives and prints from Nowinski's Holocaust collection totalling some 6,250 images and 1,548 prints, and includes the following projects: "In fitting memory; the art and politics of Holocaust memorials," the Segal Holocaust Memorial, the 50th anniversary Warsaw ghetto uprising, and the opening of the U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum. The second subdivision is Judaica photographs, totalling some 8,905 images. This segment includes three projects: the Karaite Jews, Israel, and the Soviet Jews of San Francisco.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Segal, George, 1924-; United States Holocaust Memorial Museum.; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945) in art.; Jews, Russian--California--San Francisco.; Karaites--California--Foster City.; Karaites--Egypt--Cairo--Religious life and customs.; Karaites--Israel--Religious life and customs.; Warsaw (Poland)--History--Warsaw Ghetto Uprising, 1943.; Photoprints.; Jewish photographers.; Photographers--United States.; Jewish studies.; Segal Holocaust Memorial.; Warsaw Ghetto Memorial (Warsaw, Poland); In fitting memory; the art of politics of Holocaust memorials.
Collection Contents
- Holocaust Collection, Series 1
  This series contains contact sheets and photographic prints in several sizes produced by Ira Nowinski in his photographic study of Holocaust Memorials in Europe, the United States, and Israel.
  - In Fitting Memory, Sub-series 1.1
    This sub-series contains contact sheets and photographic prints in several sizes produced by Ira Nowinski in his photographic study of Holocaust Memorials in Europe and Israel.
    - Contact sheets
      - Amsterdam: contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Austria: contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Germany: contact sheets 1 - 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        East Berlin Jewish Cemetery
      - Germany: contact sheets 5 - 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Berlin
      - Germany: contact sheets 7 - 12 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Sachsenhausen
      - Germany: contact sheets 13 - 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Buchenwald
      - Germany: contact sheets 23 - 24 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Ravensbruck
      - Germany: contact sheets 25 - 32 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Dachau
      - Germany: contact sheets 33 - 38 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        Neuengamme
      - Germany: contact sheets 39 - 41 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        Belsen - Bergen
      - Yad Vashem, Israel: contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Judah Magnes: contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - New York City: contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Paris: contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Philadelphia: contact sheets (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Prints
      - Amsterdam, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Austria: Mauthausen, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 2)
        Images from contact sheets Austria - 1 through Austria - 2
      - Austria: Mauthausen, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 3)
        Images from contact sheets Austria - 3 through Austria - 4
      - Austria: Mauthausen, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 4)
        Images from contact sheets Austria - 5
      - Germany: East Berlin Jewish Cemetery, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 5)
        Images from contact sheets Germany - 1 through Germany - 4
      - Germany: Berlin, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 6)
        Images from contact sheets Germany - 5 through Germany - 6
      - Germany: Sachsenhausen, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 7)
        Images from contact sheets Germany - 8 through Germany - 10
      - Germany: Buchenwald, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 8)
        Images from contact sheets Germany - 13
      - Germany: Buchenwald, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 9)
        Images from contact sheets Germany - 14 to Germany - 15
      - Germany: Buchenwald, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 10)
        Images from contact sheets Germany - 16 to Germany - 22
      - Germany: Ravensbruck, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 11)
        Images from contact sheet Germany - 23
      - Germany: Ravensbruck, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 12)
        Images from contact sheet Germany - 24
      - Germany: Dachau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 13)
        Images from contact sheets Germany - 25 to Germany - 26
      - Germany: Dachau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 14)
        Images from contact sheets Germany - 27 to Germany - 28
      - Germany: Dachau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 15)
        Images from contact sheet Germany - 29
      - Germany: Dachau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 16)
        Images from contact sheet Germany - 30 to Germany - 32
      - Germany: Neuengamme, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 17)
        Images from contact sheet Germany - 34 to Germany - 38
      - Germany: Bergen Belsen, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 18)
        Images from contact sheet Germany - 39 to Germany - 41
      - Germany: East Berlin Jewish Cemetery, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Germany: Buchenwald, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Germany: Ravensbruck, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Germany: Dachau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Judah Magnes, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - New York City, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Paris, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - Philadelphia, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - Yad Vashem, Israel, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 27)
        Images from contact sheets Yad Vashem - 1 through Yad Vashem - 2
      - Yad Vashem, Israel, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 4, Folder 28)
        Images from contact sheets Yad Vashem - 3 through Yad Vashem - 4
      - Yad Vashem, Israel, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 1)
        Images from contact sheets Yad Vashem - 5 through Yad Vashem - 6
      - Yad Vashem, Israel, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Images from contact sheets Yad Vashem - 12 through Yad Vashem - 14
      - Poland: Auschwitz1988, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 9 through Poland - 12
      - Poland: Auschwitz1988, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 4)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 14
      - Poland: Auschwitz, rephotographed material1993, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 5)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 98
      - Poland: Auschwitz, rephotographed material1993, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 6)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 99
      - Poland: Auschwitz, rephotographed material1993, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 7)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 100 through Poland - 102
      - Poland: Auschwitz Museum, rephotographed material [1 of 2], Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 8)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 15
      - Poland: Auschwitz Museum, rephotographed material [2 of 2], Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Poland: Auschwitz Museum, rephotographed material [1 of 3], Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 10)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 16
      - Poland: Auschwitz Museum, rephotographed material [2 of 3], Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Poland: Auschwitz Museum, rephotographed material [3 of 3], Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Poland: Belcz, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 13)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 40
      - Poland: Belcz, rephotographed material, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 14)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 121 through Poland - 122
      - Poland: Birkenau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 15)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 11, Poland - 17 through Poland - 18
      - Poland: Birkenau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 16)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 19
      - Poland: Birkenau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 17)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 20 through Poland - 22
      - Poland: Birkenau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 18)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 23 through Poland - 24
      - Poland: Birkenau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 19)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 25 through Poland - 26
      - Poland: Birkenau, rephotographed material, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 5, Folder 20)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 92 through Poland - 94
      - Poland: Birkenau, rephotographed material, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 1)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 95 through Poland - 97
      - Poland: Birkenau, rephotographed material, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 2)
        Images from unidentified contact sheets
      - Poland: Krakow, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 3)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 43 and Poland - 89 + unidentified
      - Poland: Krakow, rephotographed material, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 4)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 86 through Poland - 90
      - Poland: Lodz, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 5)
        Images from contact sheet Poland - 41
      - Poland: Lodz, rephotographed material, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 6)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 42 and Poland - 106
      - Poland: Lublin, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 7)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 44 and Poland - 106
      - Poland: Lublin, rephotographed material, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 8)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 105
      - Poland: Maidanek, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 9)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 31 through Poland - 32
      - Poland: Maidanek, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 10)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 33 through Poland - 35
      - Poland: Maidanek, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 11)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 36
      - Poland: Maidanek, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 12)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 37
      - Poland: Maidanek, rephotographed material, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 13)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 108 through Poland - 112 + unidentified
      - Poland: Plaszow [i.e. Auschwitz], Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 14)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 104
      - Poland: Plaszow [i.e. Auschwitz], rephotographed, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Poland: Sobibor, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 16)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 38 through Poland - 39
      - Poland: Sobibor, rephotographed material, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 17)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 119 through Poland - 120
      - Poland: Treblinka, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 18)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 27 through Poland - 29
      - Poland: Treblinka, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 19)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 27 through Poland - 29; Poland - 114
      - Poland: Warsaw, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 20)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 1 through Poland - 3
      - Poland: Warsaw, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 21)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 4 through Poland - 5
      - Poland: Warsaw, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 22)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 6 through Poland - 7
      - Poland: Warsaw, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 23)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 8
      - Poland: Warsaw, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 24)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 43 to Poland - 51
      - Poland: Warsaw, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 25)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 71 to Poland - 72
      - Poland: Warsaw, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 26)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 72 to Poland - 73
      - Poland: Warsaw, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 6, Folder 27)
        Images from unidentified contact sheet
    - Prints, Large
      - Austria, photographs: b&w; 34 x 28 cm. (Box 15)
      - Germany, photographs: b&w; 34 x 28 cm. (Box 15)
      - Poland, photographs: b&w; 34 x 28 cm. (Box 16)
      - Yad Vashem, Israel, photographs: b&w; 34 x 28 cm. (Box 23)
      - Poland: Auschwitz Museum, rephotographed images, photographs: b&w; 34 x 28 cm. (Box 25)
    - Prints, Oversize
      - Austria: Mauthausen, no. 1, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Austria: Mauthausen, no. 2, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Austria: Mauthausen, no. 3, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Austria: Mauthausen, no. 4, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Germany: Buchenwald, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Germany: Dachau, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Germany: Neuengamme, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Germany: Ravensbruck, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Germany: Sachsenhausen, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Poland: Auschwitz, no. 1, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 19, Folder 1)
        Images from contact sheet Poland - 9
      - Poland: Auschwitz, no. 2, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 19, Folder 2)
        Images from contact sheet Poland - 10 to Poland - 12
      - Poland: Auschwitz, no. 3, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 19, Folder 3)
        Images from contact sheet Poland - 14
      - Poland: Belcz, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Poland: Birkenau, no. 1, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 19, Folder 5)
        Images from contact sheet Poland - 17
      - Poland: Birkenau, no. 2, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 19, Folder 6)
        Images from contact sheet Poland - 19 to Poland - 20
      - Poland: Birkenau, no. 3, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 19, Folder 7)
        Images from contact sheet Poland - 21 to Poland - 22
      - Poland: Lublin, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Poland: Maidanek, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Poland: Sobibor, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Poland: Treblinka, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Poland: Warsaw, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Amsterdam, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Yad Vashem, Israel, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Poland: Auschwitz Museum, rephotographed images, no. 1, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Poland: Auschwitz Museum, rephotographed images, no. 2, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Poland: Auschwitz Museum, rephotographed images, no. 3, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Poland: Auschwitz Museum, rephotographed images, no. 4, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Prints, Mounted
      - Germany: mounted photographs, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Poland: Aushwitz: mounted photographs, no. 1, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Poland: Aushwitz: mounted photographs, no. 2, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Poland: Birkenau, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Poland: Lodz, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Poland: Lublin, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Poland: Maidanek, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Poland: Treblinka, photographs: b&w; 41 x 51 cm. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Codex Manuscript
      - The Holocaust: In Fitting Memory / Ira Nowinski, 1990, 1 codex manuscript; 13 cm. containing black and white images pasted onto sheets with annotations in the hand of the author (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 50th Anniversary of Warsaw Ghetto Uprising, Sub-series 1.2
    This series contains contact sheets and photographic prints in several sizes produced by Ira Nowinski in his photographic study of the survivors of the Warsaw Ghetto Uprising and the various monuments that were erected to those who perished.
    - Contact sheets
      - Poland: contact sheets 1 - 8 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        Warsaw
      - Poland: contact sheets 9 - 16 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        Auschwitz
      - Poland: contact sheets 17 - 26 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        Birkenau
      - Poland: contact sheets 27 - 30 (Box 1, Folder 19)
        Treblinka
      - Poland: contact sheets 31 - 37 (Box 1, Folder 20)
        Maidanek
      - Poland: contact sheets 38 - 39 (Box 1, Folder 21)
        Sobibor
      - Poland: contact sheets 40 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        Belcz
      - Poland: contact sheets 41 - 42 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        Lodz
      - Poland: contact sheets 43 (Box 1, Folder 24)
        Krakow
      - Poland: contact sheets 44 - 45 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        Lublin
      - Poland: contact sheets 46 - 56 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        50th Anniversary of Warsaw Ghetto Uprising celebrations, Warsaw (Poland)
      - Poland: contact sheets 57 - 60 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        50th Anniversary of Warsaw Ghetto Uprising celebrations, Auschwitz, Warsaw, Lublin, and Maidanek (Poland)
      - Poland: contact sheets 61 - 64 (Box 1, Folder 27)
        50th Anniversary of Warsaw Ghetto Uprising celebrations, Birkenau (Poland)
      - Poland: contact sheets 65 - 70 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        50th Anniversary of Warsaw Ghetto Uprising celebrations, Treblinka (Poland)
      - Poland: contact sheets 71 - 84 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Poland: contact sheets 85 - 91 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Poland: contact sheets 92 - 97 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        Birkenau and some images of Auschwitz
      - Poland: contact sheets 98 - 104 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Poland: contact sheets 105 - 106 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        Lublin - Lodz
      - Poland: contact sheets 107 - 113 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Poland: contact sheets 114 - 118 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Poland: contact sheets 119 - 120 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Poland: contact sheets 121 - 122 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Prints
      - People: Auschwitz, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - People: Auschwitz, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - People: Birkenau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 3)
        Images from contact sheet Poland - 61
      - People: Birkenau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 4)
        Images from contact sheet Poland - 62
      - People: Birkenau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 5)
        Images from contact sheet Poland - 64
      - People: Birkenau, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - People: Krakow, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - People: Llodz, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - People: Lublin, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - People: Maidanek, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - People: Maidanek, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - People: Treblinka, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 12)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 65 - 66
      - People: Treblinka, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 13)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 67 - 68
      - People: Treblinka, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 14)
        Images from contact sheets Poland - 69 - 70
      - People: Treblinka, Photographic prints: b&w; 21 x 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 15)